JAMES MCDONELL

Full Stack Web Developer

Adelaide, SA www.jmcdl.com james.mcdonell@outlook.com

I am a software developer with experience in front-end and back-end development for ecommerce websites and applications.

I changed careers to become a developer because I wanted the ability to not only identify problems and opportunities, but to build the solutions.

I take pride in my craft. I value doing things the right way from the start and believe that investing the effort up front always pay off in the long run. Attention to detail, constant growth and team work are my priorities.

Skills

- Writing performant HTML and CSS using best practice tools and methodologies (eg. BEM,
 Sass).
- Building clean, modern UIs with JavaScript , React , Vue , Material UI and Bootstrap .
- Making web apps and databases play nicely together, using Firebase, AWS and MySQL.
- Creating, updating, managing ecommerce integrations with Moqui Framework, Groovy,
 Shopify, EDI.
- Automating processes and fixing data, using bash scripting , RegEx and SQL.
- Version control with Git (from the command line) via Bitbucket and Github.
- Following Agile development practices, using Jira and Trello.
- Communication and building great relationships with team members, clients and managers.

Experience

Developer / Manager

TailorSoft S.A.S, Medellin (Colombia)

October 2018 - present

TailorSoft is a medium size software development company based in Colombia, working primarily with clients from the United States. Following are some of the projects I've worked on and related

inTakt - Construction scheduling web app (in progress)

- Core developer on project using React Hooks, Material UI, Firebase.
- Refactored project dialog components to use a single dialog context and reusable dialog templates.
- Built and integrated reusable custom hook for uploading user images to Firebase Storage.

Branded Online - End to end ecommerce solutions (website, marketing, fulfillment)

• Integrate Branded Online <u>ERP</u> (based on <u>Moqui</u>) with other ecommerce platforms (eg. <u>Shopify</u>, Return

Magento, Returnly, Magic).

- Edited shopify themes to work with new ERP functionality.
- Integrate ERP with fulfillment centres using EDI and CSV documents over SFTP.
- Develop core ERP features such as consuming / producing new file types.
- <u>SRE</u> support. Investigating and fixing time-sensitive bugs in production using SQL, regex, bash scripting to automate updating values in database or batch running services. Improving services and processes in codebase to prevent and alert to errors.
- Point of contact for Branded Online business/brand managers. Join daily stand-up meeting with onshore dev team and allocate tasks to TailorSoft colleagues. Perform code review for pull requests containing business sensitive changes.

Ridgecrest Herbals - US based online nutritional supplement store

- Rewrote very messy legacy HTML/CSS to improve design and make website responsive.
- Improved design and functionality of various pages, including store checkout process, using <u>Vue</u>
 and <u>Moqui</u>.

Analyst, Customer Data and Analytics

National Australia Bank, Melbourne May 2017 - May 2018

- Analysed the bank's customer data to help the marketing team review campaign impact and optimise future campaigns.
- Used SQL to compile data from a number of disparate databases into a single source and used the
 <u>R</u> programming language to produce visualisations that were used to better target credit card
 marketing.

Graduate, Finance and Strategy

National Australia Bank, Melbourne Feb 2016 - May 2017

- Undertook roles in Group Treasury, Finance Management Assurance and Internal Audit.
- Automated reporting tools and processes using Microsoft Excel and VBA
- · Responsible for preparing communications for senior management and board meetings

Education

Honours Degree of Bachelor of Economics (First Class)

• Utilised a large longitudinal data set to look at the evidence for the effectiveness of three government policies to incentivise the purchase of private health insurance.

Bachelor of Economics

University of Adelaide

2014 - 2019

- Distinction average.
- Certificate of Excellence for Advanced Mathematical Economics III, 2014
- SA Water Undergraduate Scholarship in Economics, 2009
- Academic exchange at <u>EAFIT University</u> (Medellin, Colombia) through 2011. All courses in Spanish for credit towards Bachelor of Economics

Preferred Tools

- OS: MacOS / Linux
- IDE: the JetBrains suite
- Shell: Zsh with Oh My Zsh
- Text editor: Sublime Text (primarily for RegEx)

Interests

Reading biographies - Brazilian guitar music - Exercising (somewhat reluctantly) - Attempting to play the piano - Candlelight - Financial markets and investing - Learning languages - Sleeping well - Birds

This CV was adapted from one made available by Sonja Strieder on codepen.